Tupperware Collection
Tupperware Collection
1949-2004
National Plastics Center & Museum.
0.25 linear ft.
Collection is an artificial compilation of pieces donated to the National Plastics Center & Museum. It includes sales material such as brochures and sales receipts, a copy photograph of the founder Earl Tupper with his signature, and a book of poetry published by Tupperware.
2663672
Biographical History
Earl Tupper (1907-1983) founded Tupperware Brands Corporation in 1938. Tupper's method of purifying a by-product of the oil refining process resulted in affordable polyethylene -- plastic -- products in a rainbow of colors for a wide range of kitchen and home uses. Tupper introduced the line in 1946 through department and hardware stores; sales were steady but modest until the advent of Tupperware Home Parties (based on a similar strategy developed by Stanley Home Products). The Home Parties were an immediate success and in 1958 Earl Tupper was able to sell the company for $16 million.
Tupperware spread to England and thence to Europe in the 1960s. As of 2009 Tupperware was being sold in nearly 100 countries -- still primarily through the home party method, though in some cases under alternate product names (for example, Kompakt-System in Germany and Eleganzia in England).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Tupperware Collection contains correspondence, printed material and photographs.
Correspondence includes letters between Harold A. Holtz and Earl Tupper, Harold A. Holtz and Gladys M. Leedy, and Harold A. Holtz to Lou Agnello with accompanying photographs of the opening of a time capsule with the original Tupperware set inside. Harold A. Holtz was an employee of Union Carbide/Bakelite Company and a colleague and friend of Earl Tupper.
Photographs include several photos of Earl Tupper and Harold A. Holtz.
Printed material includes a Tupperware newsletter, Tupperware Home Parties material, Tupperware demonstration booklet, and promotional material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by type of material.
Related Material
has numerous holdings in the areas of plastics and industrial design. Please refer to for a complete listing. There are also items made of Tupperware in the artifacts holdings.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Plastics; Holtz, Harold A.; Tupper, Earl Silas.; Tupperware Corporation.; Plastics industry and trade.; Plastic containers.; Plastic tableware.; Tupperware Home Parties.; Advertisements.; Brochures.; Catalogs (documents); Newsletters.; Photographs.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from National Plastics Center and Museum, 11/06/2008.
"Tupperware: A Household Word in Homes Everywhere" (1958) catalog given to Harold A. Holtz by Earl Tupper, later donated to the National Plastics Museum.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Holtz, Harold A. and Earl S. Tupper, 1953; 1978-1979,; 1982-1983; 8 letters (Box 1)
  - Holtz, Harold A. and Gladys M. Leedy, 1983; 1985; 7 letters (Box 1)
  - Holtz, Harold A. and Lou A. Agnello, 1983; 5 photographs of Tupper and Holtz are enclosed with the letters featuring a Tupperware time capsule opening event; 2 letters (Box 1)
  - Tupper, Glenn, 1983; handwritten Christmas card to Harold A. Holtz (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Earl Tupper and Harold A. Holtz, signed by Earl Tupper (Box 1)
  - Earl Tupper, Harold A. Holtz, and unknown man, one photograph is signed by Earl Tupper; 3 photographs (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Clippings, 1983; Earl Tupper's obituaries, one from The New York Times and the other from The Tico Times (Box 1)
  - Newsletter, "Sales Sentinal Magazine Section," Special Jubilee Edition, July 1958 (Box 1)
  - Promotional material, 1949; 1957,; 2002,; 2004 (Box 1)
    advertisement for a movie screening of "Tupperware!" being shown at the Museum of Fine Arts in Boston (2004)
    "American Experience: Tupperware!" postcard ad for PBS documentary (2004)
    comb and shampoo fount advertisement
    "Tupper Seals" brochure (circa 1949)
    Tupperware Tumblers brochure (1949)
    Tupperware holiday home catalog (2002)
    Wonderlier bowls advertisement (1957)
  - Tupperware Home Parties, 1953-1955; 1957-1958,; 1978,; 1980 (Box 1)
    blank receipts
    catalog (1980)
    container insert explain how to fix the top if it becomes warped (1957)
    map of the Orange Blossom Trail that highlights Tupperware Home Parties, Inc. HQ location and picture (1954)
    paper card featuring Sauce Dishes of Poly-T (1953)
    postcard featuring Tupperware Home Parties, Inc. National Headquarters (1955)
    recipe cards (1953-1954)
    "This is Tupperware" information guide
    "Tupperware: A Household Word in Homes Everywhere" (1958)
    You’re in the Company of Friends book of poems (1978)
  - Tupperware Know How Demonstration Guide, 1983 (Box 1)